鲁德 6-7⁴ 6-4 10-8 塞伦多洛 · 赛后新闻发布会
Hi Casper, Tim, congratulations.
嗨 卡斯珀 蒂姆 恭喜
First one on the board for Team Europe.
欧洲队先拿下一分
Casper, should we start with you?
卡斯珀 先从你开始？
Do you want to tell us how that feels?
能说说现在的感受吗？
Yeah, it was a great start for us.
是的 这是很好的开局
Obviously,
当然
every point on the board is important
记分牌上每一分都重要
and I knew that even though I was down.
我也知道 就算我落后
One set to love, I felt, you know,
输掉了第一盘 我也想
let's try to pull this one out for the team
要为球队把这场拼下来
and get a point on the board.
先在记分牌上拿一分
It's never over until it's
不到最后一刻
over and obviously being a match tiebreak
就不算结束 而且决胜是抢十
in the third makes you even more maybe
打在第三盘 可能让你更加
willing to really fight to win at least one set
愿意拼到至少赢下一盘
to get into a match tiebreak.
好打进抢十
So I was not pleased at all times
所以我并不是一直满意
with my game but very pleased
自己打得怎么样 但非常满意
with the win.
能赢下来
Let's have some questions.
我们开始提问吧
Congrats on the win.
恭喜获胜
Can you just talk about the tone early on?
能谈谈开局的状态吗？
It looked maybe like a little nervy like you
看上去可能有点紧张 好像你们
were both trying to find your way in.
都在努力找感觉
There were some uncharacteristic errors
有一些不像你们的失误
but you eventually kind of got your feet
但你最后还是
under you.
站稳了脚跟
Yes, it was.
是的 确实
I wasn't finding particularly my returns,
我的接发找不到感觉
second serve returns that well.
尤其是接二发
I had a plan to try to go around
我原本计划侧身
and play as many forehands
尽量多用正手
as possible and I wasn't able
但我没能
to get around the ball exactly how I wanted
按想要的方式绕到球后面
and I miss hit a few and I hit a few long
有几拍打飞了 几拍出了底线
and a little bit of maybe uncharacteristic
可能有点不像我
as you said.
就像你说的
When I play my best,
我状态最好的时候
I don't do those mistakes.
不会犯那些错
So somewhat nervy, a little bit rusty.
所以有点紧张 也有点生疏
Maybe I haven't really played a match
可能我已经好几周
at this level in a few weeks.
没打过这种级别的比赛了
Montreal was the last match I played
蒙特利尔是我上一次
at a full high level and you feel it.
打出高水平的比赛 你能感觉到
I mean, every player feels this way.
每个球员都有这种感觉
The feeling of playing good tennis is fresh.
好网球的感觉要保持新鲜
It can come and go fast
它来得快 去得也快
and hopefully a win like today can show me
希望今天这样的胜利能告诉我
that even without my perfect tennis,
就算打不出完美的网球
I can fight matches and win
我也能拼下比赛 赢下来
against good players.
哪怕对手是好球员
Hi, Casper.
嗨 卡斯珀
Obviously, the team were really trying
显然 队友们一直很努力
to pump you up and get you going.
给你打气 帮你进入状态
How much did that help?
这帮了多大的忙？
It helped a lot.
帮了很大的忙
Some of them, particularly Tim,
有几个人 尤其是蒂姆
to my side, he stayed all match
他全场都陪在我身边
and it was a tough first set to lose.
第一盘丢得很难受
I just told myself,
我就跟自己说
let's try to win for the match.
争取把这场赢下来
Give it a good effort
全力去打
and the guys pushed me and helped me
队友们推着我 帮着我
and pulled for me.
给我加油
When we entered the match tiebreak,
打进抢十的时候
it was nice to see all the guys on the bench.
看到替补席上所有队友真好
Didn't necessarily get off
抢十开局
to a great start in the match tiebreak
并不算顺利
but fought my way back
但我一路追了回来
and won some important points towards
最后阶段赢下几分关键球
the end which was fun
这很好玩
to see the teammates get cheerful
能看到队友们欢呼
and happy.
开心
Question for Tim,
问蒂姆一个问题
watching from the sidelines.
你在场边看
Was there any signs of encouragement
有没有什么迹象
that you thought that Casper can come
让你觉得卡斯珀能
through this match?
挺过这场比赛？
It was very tough
这场非常难
because there were so few opportunities.
因为机会太少了
I think Casper, talking about struggling
我觉得卡斯珀说到
a little bit on second serve return,
接二发有点吃力
I also think Cerundolo's quality
我也觉得塞伦多洛的发球质量
of serving made life difficult from the back
让他在底线
of the court.
日子很不好过
They're hitting so hard, so aggressively
他们打得又重又凶
and that's a reflection why there
这就是为什么
were no break points in the first set.
第一盘一个破发点都没有
There were a couple of break points
第二盘出现了几个破发点
in the second set and Casper was able
卡斯珀能够
to get that.
把握住
It felt like he was pushing water uphill
感觉他像是在逆水行舟
because Cerundolo was impressive.
因为塞伦多洛打得太好了
Once he got
可一旦他
into the Champions 10-point tiebreak,
打进这个抢十
anything can happen.
什么都可能发生
I think it emphasises not always
我觉得这说明 不一定
about how you start, it's how you finish.
不在开局 在于收尾
I think the way Casper finished off
我觉得卡斯珀在抢十里
in the tiebreak was very impressive.
收尾的方式非常出色
Congratulations. Casper,
恭喜 卡斯珀
you are now quite used to the Laver Cup.
你现在对拉沃尔杯已经很熟了
You had two different captains
你经历过两任不同的队长
and vice captains, so is there a difference
和副队长 有没有什么不同
between the coaching you
以前你得到的指导
had before and now the coaching you
和现在相比
have with this team?
在这支队伍得到的指导？
Yes, there are a few differences.
是的 有一些不同
With Yannick and Tim,
跟着诺阿和蒂姆
there's quite a bit more singing
唱歌要多得多
than with Bjorn and Thomas.
比跟着博格和恩奎斯特的时候
I would say both Bjorn and Yannick,
我会说博格和诺阿
they are free souls,
都是自由的灵魂
free spirits and take life fairly easy
活得洒脱 生活挺随性
and don't stress about too many things,
不会为太多事情紧张
which is nice.
这很好
Sometimes players maybe put too much
有时候球员可能给自己
pressure and stress on themselves
太多压力和紧张
and we do live a stressful life at times,
我们有时确实活得很有压力
but it's nice to have a mix of Yannick
但有诺阿这样的人很好
who sees tennis in a different way,
他看网球的方式不一样
particularly to me and also contrast to Tim
尤其跟我比 也跟蒂姆形成对比
who watches a lot of tennis
蒂姆看很多网球
and commentates a lot of tennis.
也解说很多网球
He sees us almost not every week,
他见我们不是每周
but kind of month in, month out
但差不多每个月
at the big tournaments
在大赛上
and he knows strength and weaknesses
他了解我们每个人
in all of our games.
打法里的强项和弱点
Both of them challenge me in a good way
他们俩都给了我很好的挑战
because they come a lot more to the net
因为他们更常上网
or they're used to it than I am doing
或者比我更习惯上网
and they play a bit of a flatter ball
他们击球更平一些
and challenge me to do that as well.
也逼着我那样去打
It's nice to hear other opinions
听到不同的意见很好
that I haven't heard in many years from Tim
多年来我没听过的 来自蒂姆
and Yannick.
和诺阿
A question for Tim.
问蒂姆一个问题
In terms of watching tennis,
说到看球
when you're watching your players
你看自己队员的时候
as a vice captain, do you watch it differently
作为副队长 看法会不一样吗
than if you're watching a game as a pundit
跟你作为评论员
or as a commentator?
或者解说员相比？
No, not at all.
不 完全不会
I've got a lot more vested interest watching
我现在看这些比赛
these matches
感情投入多得多
because I'm part of the team,
因为我是团队的一员
but I'm always looking strategically
但我一直在从战术上看
when I'm commentating who's doing what
解说的时候 看谁在做什么
and why is one person winning,
为什么这个人能赢
what are the strengths and weaknesses.
优势和短板是什么
As Casper referenced, having been working
就像卡斯珀说的 我过去五年
in the media for the last five years,
一直在媒体工作
I'm seeing a lot of these players play.
看了很多这些球员的比赛
There aren't too many secrets or things
没有太多秘密
that I haven't been able to watch.
是我没看过的
This is where the coaching element
这就是执教的部分
is not teaching.
不是教技术
There's teaching and coaching.
教技术和执教是两回事
Coaching is about strategy.
执教讲的是战术
It's about game plans and trying
是比赛计划 是尽量
to help with the individual match -ups
帮每一场对位出主意
because you only have to be better
因为你只需要比
than one player.
一个对手更好
It was very close today, but Casper was able
今天很接近 但卡斯珀能够
to be better than Cerundolo
比塞伦多洛更好
and that's why we got the point.
所以我们拿到了这一分
Okay, thanks very much.
好 非常感谢